<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Invest with R</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Invest with R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting S&amp;P 500 Returns with R (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/post/forecasting-s-p-500-returns-with-r-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/forecasting-s-p-500-returns-with-r-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I am not a data scientist, but I am an R, investing, and data science enthusiast.
1. IntroductionIs it possible to predict stock returns? We will look at a group of 500 large U.S. companies and try to identify any historical patterns that can be used to predict future returns. Specifically, we will focus on the S&amp;amp;P 500 stock index which represents the stock performance of a diverse group of 500 of the largest U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Portfolio Construction</title>
      <link>/post/optimal-portfolio-construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/optimal-portfolio-construction/</guid>
      <description>Optimal Portfolio ConstructionIn this article we will compare several portfolio construction methodologies. We will evaluate the Modern Portfolio Theory and the Risk Parity portfolio and Resampled Efficient Frontier approaches.
The Modern Portfolio Theory approach attempts to maximize the return of a group of assets (a portfolio) for the level of risk borne by those assets. One complaint of this approach is its tendency to lead to overconcentrated portfolios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Distressed Stocks</title>
      <link>/post/finding-distressed-stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/finding-distressed-stocks/</guid>
      <description>Finding Stocks at Risk of Financial DistressThe goal of this analysis is to isolate stocks that are particularly risky to the long-only investor. A probability of distress will be computed based on observable financial data. The model was derived in academia and later utilized in a book titled “Quantitative Value” (2013).
The FormulaLogit Probability of Financial Distress (LPFD)A logistic regression model is used to estimate whether a firm is in financial distress or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 1</title>
      <link>/itemized/item1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/itemized/item1/</guid>
      <description>App 1 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 2</title>
      <link>/itemized/item2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/itemized/item2/</guid>
      <description>App 2 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 3</title>
      <link>/itemized/item3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/itemized/item3/</guid>
      <description>App 3 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 4</title>
      <link>/itemized/item4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/itemized/item4/</guid>
      <description>App 4 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>—title: “Hello R Markdown”author: “Frida Gomam”date: 2015-07-23T21:13:14-05:00categories: [“R”]tags: [“R Markdown”, “plot”, “regression”]—R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>&amp;mdash; author: Theme author categories: - Hugo date: &amp;ldquo;2014-09-28&amp;rdquo; description: Learn how to create a theme on Hugo featured: pic03.jpg featuredalt: Pic 3 featuredpath: date linktitle: &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; tags: - tutorial title: Creating a New Theme type: post draft: true &amp;mdash; Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/blog/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>&amp;mdash; author: Unknown Author categories: - Go date: &amp;ldquo;2014-04-02&amp;rdquo; description: &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; featured: pic02.jpg featuredalt: Pic 2 featuredpath: date linktitle: &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; title: (Hu)go Template Primer type: post draft: true &amp;mdash; Hugo uses the excellent go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/blog/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>&amp;mdash; author: Hugo author categories: - Hugo date: &amp;ldquo;2014-04-02&amp;rdquo; description: &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; featured: pic01.jpg featuredalt: Pic 1 featuredpath: date linktitle: &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; title: Getting Started with Hugo type: post &amp;mdash; Step 1. Install Hugo Go to hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your os and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at installing hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&amp;mdash; author: Migrating author categories: - Hugo - Jekyll date: &amp;ldquo;2014-03-10&amp;rdquo; description: &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; featured: &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; featuredalt: &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; featuredpath: &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; linktitle: &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo; title: Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll type: post draft: true &amp;mdash; Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>