<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on Invest with R</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on Invest with R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting S&amp;P 500 Returns with R (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/post/forecasting-s-p-500-returns-with-r-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/forecasting-s-p-500-returns-with-r-part-1/</guid>
      <description>1. IntroductionIs it possible to predict stock returns? We will look at a group of 500 large U.S. companies and try to identify any historical patterns that can be used to predict future returns. Specifically, we will focus on the S&amp;amp;P 500 stock index which represents the stock performance of 500 of the largest U.S. companies.
Why predict S&amp;amp;P 500 returns? Millions of people are invested in U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Portfolio Construction</title>
      <link>/post/optimal-portfolio-construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/optimal-portfolio-construction/</guid>
      <description>Optimal Portfolio ConstructionIn this article we will compare several portfolio construction methodologies. We will evaluate the Modern Portfolio Theory and the Risk Parity portfolio and Resampled Efficient Frontier approaches.
The Modern Portfolio Theory approach attempts to maximize the return of a group of assets (a portfolio) for the level of risk borne by those assets. One complaint of this approach is its tendency to lead to overconcentrated portfolios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Distressed Stocks</title>
      <link>/post/finding-distressed-stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/finding-distressed-stocks/</guid>
      <description>Finding Stocks at Risk of Financial DistressThe goal of this analysis is to isolate stocks that are particularly risky to the long-only investor. A probability of distress will be computed based on observable financial data. The model was derived in academia and later utilized in a book titled “Quantitative Value” (2013).
The FormulaLogit Probability of Financial Distress (LPFD)A logistic regression model is used to estimate whether a firm is in financial distress or not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>